TOMMY: Oh, there's a woman.
Yeah.
A woman.
Who I love.
And I got close.
In the bleak midwinter...
At some point in the near future,
Mr. Churchill will want to speak to you
in person.
Mr. Shelby,
he has a job for you.
(PANTING)
We will be in touch.
(THEME SONG PLAYING)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
Oh, thank you.
-(BABY CRYING)
-I'm going to take him.
Some of us know the words.
Trot on.
(SINGING) In the bleak mid-winter
Frosty wind made moan
Earth stood hard as iron
Trot on.
Water like a stone
Snow had fallen, snow on snow
Snow on snow
In the bleak mid-winter
Long ago
(TRUMPETS BLOWING)
(WEDDING MUSIC PLAYING)
Here come the fucking cavalry.
Late as usual.
JEREMIAH: Dearly beloved.
We are gathered here today
to join together in holy matrimony
Thomas Michael Shelby
and Grace Helen Burgess.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
(INDISTINCT)
JEREMIAH:
Do you, Thomas Michael Shelby,
take Grace Helen Burgess
to be your lawful wedded wife?
TOMMY: I do.
Do you, Grace Helen Burgess,
solemnly swear to love, honor,
and obey till death do you part?
GRACE: I do.
JEREMIAH: I now pronounce you
husband and wife.
(ALL CHEERING)
Get out of it!
(ALL TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
-Go on, take the photograph!
-(CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKING)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
Tommy.
Arthur, get the bastards in the house.
I will. I will. John! John-Boy!
Get 'em in the house, all of 'em.
Go on, all of you! Back to the house!
Go on!
(ALL CHEERING)
(MUSIC CONTINUES PLAYING)
(ALL CHEERING AND APPLAUDING)
(BALLROOM MUSIC PLAYING)
All right, Pol. Tell the Lee girls
I've counted all the paintings.
And, Pol, some people here
are not on the list.
Curly, Charlie. Kitchen.
-Time?
-Five minutes.
Actually, we were told on the train
there'd be cocaine.
Jeremiah, John-Boy, kitchen, let's go.
I swear to God them fucking Cavalry boys
are asking for it.
Uh, I was told to ask someone young.
Will there be cocaine?
Sweetheart, I am young, informed
and, uh, very well-equipped.
You chose your man wisely.
Go on, kitchen now.
Arthur, this lady
wants to play in the snow.
No, no snow today. No snow today.
Kitchen, come on.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
(ALL LAUGHING)
I just wish Tommy was here.
-Where are they?
-JOHNNY: I don't know, Tommy.
-Arthur, John, where are they?
-I don't know.
-I am telling you now, we got lost.
-Come on.
You really need to do a map. Thomas.
Right, boys, you're all here.
Today, this is my fucking wedding day.
Yeah, and you said
there'd be no bloody uniforms.
Nevertheless... Nevertheless, John...
Despite the bad blood,
I'll have none of it on my carpet.
Now for Grace's sake,
nothing will go wrong.
Those bastards out there are her family.
And if you fuckers do anything
to embarrass her,
your kin, your cousins, your horses,
your fucking kids, you do anything...
-JOHN: Tom?
-To... What?
What about snow?
Yeah, their women are sports,
I'll say that...
No. No. No.
No cocaine.
No cocaine. No sport.
No telling fortunes. No racing.
No fucking sucking petrol
out of their fucking cars.
And, you, Charlie,
stop spinning yarns about me, eh?
I'm just trying to sell you to them, Tom.
But the main thing is,
you bunch of fuckers,
despite the provocation from the cavalry,
no fighting.
Oi!
No fighting.
No fucking fighting.
(SHOUTING) No fucking fighting!
Good.
-Get the fuck off me!
-(GLASS SHATTERS)
You're needed downstairs.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Grace, you're needed downstairs.
People are hungry.
I was putting Charles to sleep. (SIGHS)
I'll come down,
but not with you like this.
All right, fine.
GRACE: Tommy.
I thought today was the reason
for the way you've been acting lately.
I know there's business on your mind.
-And I know there always will be.
-Yeah.
Look, I am sorry
that they wore their uniforms.
Yeah, they fucking did, eh.
They fucking did.
But I can tell it's more than that.
You've been like this for weeks.
(CLEARS THROAT)
I need you to tell me
that it's business making you like this.
And not regret over me.
Say it out loud
and I'll know if it's true.
(CLICKS TONGUE)
It's business, Grace.
And bad, bad business it is, all around.
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
And I'm scared, Grace.
I'm scared for you.
I'm scared for the baby.
And this is how I am when I'm scared.
It is unfamiliar to you, but not to me.
I can... I can fucking be scared
and carry on.
And it's not pleasant to look at
and no joy to be around.
All right?
I'm sorry. (SNIFFLES)
We've just made vows to share everything.
Tell me what it is you're afraid of.
-(MUSIC PLAYING)
-(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
-Stand up. Stand up, stand up.
-Don't.
Arthur's speech.
I'm scared of fucking Arthur's speech.
All right?
Me, too.
Tommy, what are you doing?
Tommy.
There's half the British Army
waiting for us downstairs.
They're King's Irish.
We waited two weeks in the mud for them.
Tommy. (CHUCKLES)
There are things, that if I take them off,
I won't be able to put back on...
-That's good.
-(CHUCKLES)
Hello, Mrs. Shelby.
-I'm sorry for being busy in my head.
-(CHUCKLES)
Now let's complete the ceremony.
Hey, Vincent, Vincent, Vincent.
What do you call an animal
with a prick halfway up its back?
A cavalry horse. (LAUGHING)
He got... He gets it.
Fuck it. Fuck it.
Where the bloody hell are they?
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
You're best man, Arthur. Go and find them.
Yeah.
ADA: That's completely nonsense.
You know, we're part of a serious
political movement and organization.
They're not "secret little meetings,"
they're just meetings.
We talk about the world,
about the people in it,
about our current political landscape
and what's going on.
You know, we really need to re-evaluate
the way our government...
(WHISPERING INDISTINCTLY)
-POLLY: Very strange indeed.
-He's looking over.
What?
He's coming. He bloody is.
Fuck. It's the wrong one.
What do you mean "the wrong one"?
How many are there?
There's two, giving me the eye.
I prefer the other one. He looks harmless.
It must be that bloody lipstick
Tommy brought you back from New York.
I couldn't help noticing
you are unaccompanied.
I also am alone. May I join you?
ARTHUR: Tommy?
Oh. (SNIFFLES)
Didn't see a thing. Did not see a thing.
Sorry, brother.
I need you downstairs.
It's all right. We're done. (SIGHS)
-You good?
-Yeah.
-Never been better.
-Yeah?
-Are you drunk?
-Huh? No.
No.
Here.
All right, it's just one drink, then.
Linda's a good woman, Arthur.
Good whiskey.
A good man needs to
hold out sometimes, eh?
(SIGHS)
So, uh, do I mention this
in my speech, then, eh?
Not unless you want to get cut, Arthur.
ARTHUR: Sorry, sister.
TOMMY: Right. Look.
Tell the maids to break out the champagne.
We'll be down in a minute.
Champagne, yeah. Okay.
-I got it right here. I'm ready.
-Good. Good.
Where are you from?
I'm a refugee.
From where?
Russia.
In the past few months,
Thomas has developed
some business interests with Russia.
I see he has confided in you.
Hmm.
You need his permission
to even speak to me.
My senior position
within the Shelby company
means I don't often have to ask permission
from anyone
to do anything.
So perhaps you'll just tell me
why the fuck you're talking
Russian business on Thomas's wedding day.
LIZZIE: Hold on, wait a second.
-So you're saying I'm not allowed a man...
-It's about your choice of man.
LIZZIE: I'm not allowed a man on my arm?
MICHAEL: Thomas says
that they're the rules.
LIZZIE: Fucking parish bastard!
Michael, speeches. Come on.
Arthur. You know
why he didn't come, don't you?
Why who didn't come?
My bloody man.
Oh, you mean the wop?
LIZZIE: I just heard there was a fire
at his restaurant midnight last night.
And a smashed back window
and a smell of petrol.
Lizzie, we tried to talk some sense
into you.
We did checks on him.
He's had five different names
in the last six years,
and he's got connections
with the Naples boys.
ARTHUR: Come on, Michael.
What do you know about love?
About when lightning strikes.
So, it was lightning, hmm? Not petrol.
I thought you were
off the whiskey, Arthur.
Yeah, I am. Having a couple now and again
to remind myself why I don't drink it.
(CHUCKLES)
You set fire to his restaurant
to stop him coming.
You have no right to choose
who I step out with in my own time!
(MICHAEL CLEARS THROAT)
Lizzie, you now have an important position
in this company.
You got the order, same as us.
You can do it.
Until further notice...
No fraternizing with the foreigners.
Yeah, well, you can tell Tommy from me
all the girls in the office think
he's losing his fucking mind!
To the bride.
ALL: The bride.
-The bride.
And now, (CLEARS THROAT)
according to tradition,
my best man will say a few words.
Go on! Here he goes! Go on, Arthur!
Right, um... I'm not one for speeches.
-Sing, then!
-ARTHUR: I will later, John.
But, uh, I do, uh...
I do have some words written down here
on this piece of paper.
This doesn't include everything
that I want to say.
Arthur, just, uh...
Just read what we wrote down, eh?
-I will, I will.
-Mmm-hmm.
But...
First... First, uh, a few words from...
From the heart.
Um...
This man here, my brother Tommy,
helped me survive through
some of the worst times.
(COUGHS AND CLEARS THROAT)
It's a wedding, Arthur, tell a joke.
JOHN: Yeah, tell a joke.
What I am trying to say is that...
(STUTTERS) My brother
and the love of a good woman
pulled me through that time.
Now Tommy also
has the love of a good woman.
Her name's Grace.
Like the grace of the good Lord.
And even though
the circumstances of their union
was tragic...
All right. Let's, uh... Arthur.
Let's raise a toast, eh?
To, uh... (CLEARS THROAT)
To love, to peace, to marriage.
-And to marriage.
-To marriage.
JOHN: Well done, Arthur, beautiful speech.
Really nice.
Really, really nice.
Where is he fucking going?
-I think I messed it up.
-No, not a bit.
-Hmm.
-You spoke with such truth.
And God heard you.
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
TOMMY: Can I have a word
with my brother, please, Linda?
-What he was going to say was beautiful.
-Mmm-hmm.
Alone, please.
All right. Come here.
Come here.
(TOMMY SIGHS)
We talked about this, Arthur.
That's why we wrote it all down.
Most of Grace's side don't even know
her husband killed himself.
They think it was an accident.
-Oh, I know.
-You know.
-Yeah.
What do you think I am? Hmm?
What do you think I am, Tommy, eh?
-You think I'm a fucking idiot, don't you?
-All right, boys.
-Come on, have a good night.
-You think I would say it...
-Come on, then. That's okay.
-You keep walking, you nosy bastards.
-Arthur. Fucking hell.
-All right. You stay away from me.
You stay away from me. I've had enough.
Ah!
Shit.
-(GROANING)
-Yeah. Yeah.
Ah, shit.
Three shots I've had, that's it.
-TOMMY: I know.
-I drew the line.
I know.
I know you've turned a corner, Arthur.
-Yeah.
-I know.
-Mmm-hmm.
-I'm your best man.
-I know.
I wasn't going to tell no one.
(WHISPERS) It's all right.
It's done. Get up. Get up.
-Get up.
-(GROANS)
Right.
The Russians have made contact.
We have to get used to
how these bastards operate.
For them,
family is a weakness,
and they go after them.
For me, family is my strength.
And there's business to be done.
And I need you.
Now, fuck speeches, fuck weddings.
You're my best man every fucking day.
-Okay.
-Yeah.
Now go and get John, get him sobered up.
Find Johnny Dogs.
It's the Russians
through the smoke tonight.
All right.
Good.
And, Arthur?
In future, it's not always right
to listen to Linda.
-Yeah? Yeah.
-Yeah.
-(MUSIC PLAYING)
-(PEOPLE LAUGHING)
It's full of gypsies and blacks.
Grace says he exports automobiles
to the colonies.
TOMMY: Pol, now.
So what does he say?
He won't meet you
unless you give us the name.
What name?
We were told to ask for a code name
when contact was made.
Constantine. The code is Constantine.
Tommy said no racing, no gambling.
Yeah, he's changed his mind.
-Right. Don't worry Finn, okay?
-Right. (CHUCKLES)
Cavalry boys ride like a sack of stones,
all right?
John. John, there's an awful lot of
King's shillings around here today.
Now, out of loyalty to the regiment,
they'll all be putting their money
on this bad boy
-that I filled up with morphine and water.
-(BOTH LAUGHING)
Here. Tommy's all right if I, uh,
do the book, is he?
He said betting's okay, but all proceeds
go to the Shelby Foundation charity.
Oh, is this charity of his for real, then?
He says he wants to be seen
giving back to the poor of Birmingham.
So that'll be me, John.
Myself.
If I can't earn a shilling here tonight.
Huh?
They'll make him
the fucking Lord Mayor next.
Mmm, that's the idea, Charlie-Boy.
Fucking hell.
Right, all you lot
make as much noise and fuss as you can.
Especially fucking you.
So we're a fucking distraction, John,
is it?
-(BOTH LAUGHING)
-Huh?
Tommy is doing business on a night
he should be just fucking.
(LAUGHING)
Right, place your bets with me.
Your favorites. Your favorites.
Come on, boys.
'Cause I hope my boy Finn
doesn't fall off that fucking horse.
Come on.
For charity.
CURLY: Shut up.
ARTHUR: Oh, you found it.
We nearly gave up.
Did he tell you
what my business with him is?
The same shit the Turks used to smoke.
I wonder,
why does he trust his aunt
more than his brothers?
(CHUCKLES)
TOMMY: Go and watch the race, boys.
The Turk's clean.
I am Russian.
Same fucking thing.
So you make contact on my wedding day.
You now have very powerful enemies.
At the Soviet Embassy
and within your own government.
You are being watched,
at your house, your office, your clubs,
your bars.
You best be quick or I'll be missed.
Now where's the money?
The Duke's niece is
bringing it from London.
I was told money on contact.
Ten thousand in US dollars.
My employer only trusts
members of his family with cash.
She will be at Snow Hill station at 10:00.
(CHUCKLES)
A woman alone in Birmingham
with $10,000 in cash.
-And she also has a revolver.
-Oh, I see.
I thought you trusted women.
I don't trust Birmingham.
I'll have her picked up.
-By who?
-By the police, pal.
This is our city.
(ALL CHEERING)
ARTHUR: Fucking beautiful horse, Tom.
Beautiful.
-He's a natural, that boy.
-Yeah.
Good posture. Rides like Dad.
TOMMY: All right, listen to me.
Tell Johnny Dogs and his boys
to light a fire in the woods,
a big one, to take meat.
And send Finn to watch the gates.
Moss is bringing someone.
CHARLOTTE: You don't?
I just needed to bring you somewhere
nobody could see.
But your friend gave this to me.
He said you all did it.
Not me.
But it's all right. Go on.
(MICHAEL CHUCKLES)
I see you don't, either.
-Don't be silly, everyone does.
-So go on, then.
-(SIGHS) Cut the snow.
-We call it Tokyo.
We call it whatever the customer calls it.
In London,
we were told you are all gangsters.
So that's why you got on the train
to dirty, old Birmingham.
For a dirty, old night.
You don't look like the others.
That's the idea.
I put it all together,
but I don't partake.
You see, I've got a bright future,
you see.
Mapped out.
But you want me to be like them,
don't you?
There's a cavalry officer
stationed in Ceylon.
And when his tour of duty ends in March,
we'll be engaged.
So I have a bright future, too.
Mapped out.
But you want to try things first.
(SNORTS)
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
No. Keep it.
As if I were a whore.
Well, if that's the game you want to play.
(PEOPLE LAUGHING
AND TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
Polly.
Hello, Grace.
You look absolutely beautiful.
Welcome to the family.
Oh, I see. Tommy's orders.
No upsets tonight.
Your hair, everything, beautiful.
Do you know where he is?
Yes. Yes, I do.
You know, Tommy really wants to keep
certain things a secret from me.
It's very hard when you're man and wife.
We were late coming down
because we were having sex.
So afterwards, he told me everything.
Royalist Russians buying weapons
to fight the Bolsheviks in Georgia.
A lost cause, Tommy says.
And Churchill, that he's the go-between.
But it's against government policy
so everything must be kept a secret.
You know it's begun?
They started the business tonight?
No. (SIGHS)
I didn't.
But you just told me.
So, thank you.
Let's not forget
I used to do this for a living.
Oh, I haven't forgotten, sweetheart.
It's only Thomas that's forgotten
what you are.
MAN: Ladies and Gentlemen.
The bride and the groom
will now dance alone.
(ALL CHEERING)
(MUSIC PLAYING)
Polly just told me
there is business being done.
I didn't ask them to come.
Tommy, please don't let
anything happen tonight.
Just get this business done
and get away from things like this.
I'll run the foundation,
you'll run the tracks and sell cars.
Promise me.
Hmm?
A wedding vow.
I promise.
No guns in the house
-and Charles will never see one.
-(CHUCKLES)
I love you, Thomas Shelby.
You keep us safe.
I love you.
And I promise I will make us safe.
MAN: Ladies and gentlemen,
you may now join.
Gate house, come on.
(ENGINE STOPS)
Tommy, Arthur, Collins.
May I introduce you to the
Grand Duchess Tatiana Petrovna,
from Tbilisi, Georgia.
Grand Duchess, may I introduce you
to the Shelby brothers.
Small Heath, Birmingham.
And, uh, good luck with this one, Tom.
Give me the money.
I was told to give it to Mr. Kaledin.
Whoever it is up there,
he gave the wrong name.
We asked him the name
and he gave the wrong one.
-What name did he give?
-No.
I don't trust any of you.
Now you give me the money.
I know Mr. Kaledin by sight from Tbilisi.
Is his hair dark?
The instructions I was given
was anyone using the wrong code name
was an infiltrator for the Soviet Embassy.
Just let me go to the house.
I do not want this shit
anywhere near my fucking house.
All I know is "no variations."
That's from Churchill himself.
Whoever it is up at the house,
he gave the wrong fucking name.
And you do this to me
on my fucking wedding day.
(CLICKS TONGUE)
The money is in the car, Mr. Shelby.
Fetch it out and count it.
Good. Finn.
(COUGHS)
Yeah. We're good.
You can go. Moss... (CLEARS THROAT)
Can you do it?
Can you kill?
Moss, you take the "Duchess"
back to Birmingham.
MOSS: Right-o Tom.
Come on, love.
That's right.
(PEOPLE LAUGHING)
You have got to tell me the reason,
otherwise I'll never be able to trust you.
The truth is,
that I slept with the wife of
one of the colonels who sat for me.
But that was 12 years ago.
And the aristocracy
don't believe in forgiveness.
Neither do the Shelbys.
(ENGINE STOPS)
So, we kill him?
He's a red.
We're being paid by the whites.
It's part of the contract.
Contract.
We should never have got into this, Tom.
There was no choice.
"A factory break-in,"
that's what you said.
Yeah. And that's what it is.
There's just some shit that goes with it.
And who shovels it? Hmm?
Who fucking shovels it? Eh?
I fucking know.
-Arthur?
-I fucking know.
Arthur.
There's 10 times where that's coming from,
10 times.
For lifting vehicles
off a fucking shop floor.
Vehicles, Tommy. Fucking vehicles.
-Nothing about tanks.
-Yeah.
Arthur, you listen to me.
You listen to me, all right?
There are powerful people in this country
who want to help these mad bastards,
including the King, Churchill
and half the fucking Tory Party.
And if we refuse, Arthur,
if we fucking refuse,
they will see to it
that we hang for one of our many sins.
Now, we've never earned money
like this. Never.
We'll use it to buy
the wharf at Boston docks.
That's why I've asked for dollars.
And when it's done,
it's business as usual.
Come on, brother. It's my wedding night.
(CHATTERING)
-Where's John?
-Looking for Esme.
Right.
I'm Ruben Oliver, portrait artist.
I really enjoyed the depiction of you
in the dining room.
[In Romani] Johnny's lit a fire.
Keep people dancing.
Nice to meet you, Mr. Oliver.
Johnny, ragtime.
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
(SIGHS)
So, where were we?
-Crimea.
-Oh, I mean before I bored you with war.
(CHUCKLES)
-Politics.
-Ah, yes.
You're the only one in your family
who is a communist?
Some of them are,
they just don't know it.
(CHUCKLES) And you are
a very close family, yes?
Mmm, always within punching distance.
What does that mean?
It means, "Yeah, we're a close family."
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
Arthur?
I do apologize for the interruption.
There is a woman here
to see you, Mr. Kaledin.
She just arrived.
(LAUGHTER AND INDISTINCT TALKING)
So, Tatiana made it from London safe?
-Yes.
-Where is she?
Out by the stables.
Can I use the lavatory?
You can piss outside by the stables.
No!
(SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
(GROANING)
(MEN TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
Very sensible idea, Mr. Shelby.
Clear the air away from the ladies.
(GRUNTING)
We are rather like generals here,
aren't we?
Watching our men do battle.
We are a bit too close to the fighting
to be generals, surely.
(SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
(PANTING)
(SCREAMING)
(TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
You know, Mr. Shelby, some of us only
agreed to come today to bless this union
because of your exemplary war record.
But as Grace's uncle
and a kind of father to her
for many years,
I'm still deeply uneasy
about the many stories of corruption
and violence.
(BOTH STRUGGLING)
(SCREAMING)
Drink the fucking wine and smile.
That's what I'm doing.
ARTHUR: Oh, you got me good.
Oh, you fucking bastard.
(ALL SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
No foul!
(PANTING)
KALEDIN: Don't shoot.
No!
Oh, for the love of God, don't shoot.
No! No!
-No!
-For the love of God...
-No! No! No!
-No!
-For the love of God.
(GUNSHOT)
-What was that?
-(BOTH PANTING)
It's probably just a car back-firing.
(PANTING)
It wasn't the day I was expecting.
Nor me.
It's over now.
Tomorrow it'll be just us.
(SIGHS)
Come here.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
CURLY: Go on.
You've had a great night.
The water froze in my car.
Uh, they said I could stay.
I know, this is preposterous.
Plenty of other rooms to stay in.
-Goodnight, Mr. Oliver.
-You have my card.
Anytime you're in London,
we could have tea.
ARTHUR: I went looking for you.
I thought you'd be in here.
I knew it.
I wanted to end with a bit of peace.
(WHISPERS) Yeah.
Look what I found.
It's beautiful. Thanks.
Arthur, you mustn't worry about
what happened with the speech.
What was in your heart was beautiful.
God hears all the speeches
that don't get said.
And isn't it nice to still be yourself
at this time of night?
Close your eyes, Arthur,
and spend a minute thinking about that.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
(BABY CRYING)
TOMMY: It's all right.
It's all right.
(SHUSHING)
(INAUDIBLE)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
More money than all those
fucking toffs put together, eh?
And you're willing to gamble it all
on one robbery.
I'm a gambling man, Pol.
(THEME SONG PLAYING)